听力考试现在开始。二零。二四年河南省普通高中招生考试英语。一听力理解。
understand B, and 1.
第一节，听下面五段对话，每段对话后。有一个小题：从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳答案。每段对话读两遍。
me, how can I get to the bookstore?
The bookstore? Go down this road and turn left at the second corner.
You will see it next to a hospital.
Excuse me, how can I get to the bookstore?
The bookstore? Go down this road and turn left at the second corner.
You will see it next to a hospital.
2. Jack, what's your favorite subject?
History. What about you, Mary?
I like English best.
Jack, what's your favorite subject?
History. What about you, Mary?
I like English best.
3. What did you do last Sunday?
It was windy, so I went to fly kites with my friends.
What did you do last Sunday?
4. Hi Bruce, can you come to my birthday party on Friday?
Sure, Helen. I'll bring my sister Maggie with me.
Hi Bruce, can you come to my birthday party on Friday?
5. Tom, have you finished your math homework?
Not yet. It's a little hard for me.
What about you?
Me neither. I also have some problems with it.
Let's go to Mr.
Black's office for help.
That's a good idea.
Tom, have you finished your math homework?
Not yet. It's a little hard for me.
What about you?
Me neither. I also have some problems with it.
Let's go to Mr.
Black's office for help.
That's a good idea.
第二节：听下面几段对话或独白。每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的
B, and Anything else?
三个选项中选出最佳答案。每段对话或独白读两遍。听下面一段对话，回答第六至第七两个小题。
No, thanks. That would be 45 yuan.
Can I help you?
Yes. Do you have a table for two?
This way, please.
We have a table by the window.
Thank you. Are you ready to order?
Yes. We want some beef and vegetables, please.
Anything else? No, thanks.
Okay. That would be yuan.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至第九两个小题。
Sally, I want to climb Laojun Mountain this summer.
Really? I heard Laojun Mountain is hard to climb.
You'd better get well prepared for it.
I've already asked about it.
I just need a pair of good sports shoes.
And I think you should do some exercise every day.
You are right.
Then I'll be strong enough to climb the mountain.
you. You are right.
you a good time.
听下面一段独白，回答第十。
to twelfth three small questions.
Hello, boys and girls.
Attention, please.
Our school is going to the old people's home this Saturday afternoon.
And we need some students to join us.
We will help to clean the yard, water flowers, and put on the play.
The activity will be from three o to five o
If you are interested, you can go and ask Mr.
for more information.
It's a good chance to do some social practice.
Come and join us.
That's all. Thank you.
Hello, boys and girls.
Attention, please.
Our school is going to the old people's home this Saturday afternoon.
And we need some students to join us.
We will help to clean the yard, water flowers, and put on the play.
The activity will be from three o to five o
If you are interested,
you can go and ask Mr.
Li for more information.
It's a good chance to do some social practice.
Come and join us.
That's all. Thank you.
听下面一段对话，回答第十三至第十五三个小题。
Yes. And tell me again, please.
Which bus shall we take?
No. bus. It will take about 20 minutes to get there.
Got it. What should I take with me?
Well, an ID card is needed.
OK. Hey, George.
Hey, Emily. I'm excited about our plan for next Wednesday.
Me too. I can't wait.
We are going to have fun.
Will this be your first visit to Henan Museum?
Yes. And tell me again, please.
Which bus shall we take?
No. bus. It will take about 20 minutes to get there.
Got it. What should I take with me?
Well, an ID card is needed.
OK. want talk about some hobbies that can help us to become better.
第三节，听。下面一篇短文，按照你所听内容的先后顺序，将下列图片排序。短文读两遍。
First of all, I think reading is a good hobby.
Reading can help us learn more about the world around us.
Swimming can be a good choice.
There is nothing better than going for a swim on a hot summer day.
If you love music,
can choose to play the violin.
Sweet music can help you forget about worries and relax yourself.
Most people like running.
Running is good for both mind and body.
But it's not easy to keep running every day.
Also, basketball is popular.
Through playing basketball, we can learn teamwork and make many new friends.
That's all for my speech.
Thanks for your listening.
Hello everyone. It's my turn to make a speech today.
As we know, play an important part in our daily life.
So I'm going to talk about some hobbies that can help us to become better.
First of all, I think reading is a good hobby.
Reading can help us learn more about the world around us.
Swimming can be a good choice.
There is nothing better than going for a swim on a hot summer day.
you love music, can choose to play the violin.
Sweet music can help you forget about worries and relax yourself.
Most people like running.
Running is good for both mind and body.
But it's not easy to keep running every day.
Also, basketball is popular.
Through playing basketball, we can learn teamwork and make many new friends.
That's all for my speech.
Thanks for your listening.
听力考试到此结束，请同学们继续答题。